<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>ProvenCFO - Trusted Financial Partner</title>
 <link href="http://www.provencfo.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.provencfo.com"/>
 <updated>2019-12-21T19:43:16-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.provencfo.com/</id>


 
 <entry>
   <title>Discovering your passion</title>
   <link href="http://www.provencfo.com/blog/business/2015/10/23/Discoveringyourpassion"/>
   <updated>2015-10-23T01:19:19-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.provencfo.com/blog/business/2015/10/23/Discoveringyourpassion</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been reading and writing responses on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt; and stumbled on a very interesting question: “How can a person discover his/her passion?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;I found one response by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Chuck-Eesley&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chuck Eesley&lt;/a&gt; particularly inspiring. He posted a link to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.stanford.edu/news/2014/june/gates-commencement-remarks-061514.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2014 Stanford Commencement Address by Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates&lt;/a&gt;. You can also watch a &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/wug9n5Atk8c&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; of the address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wug9n5Atk8c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;Here are some great quotes I’ve pulled from that speech: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;“Optimism for me isn't a passive expectation that things will get better; it's a conviction that we can make things better”&lt;cite&gt; - Melinda&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“But we want to make the strongest case we can for the power of optimism. Even in dire situations, optimism can fuel innovation and lead to new tools to eliminate suffering.”&lt;cite&gt; - Bill&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“But in the course of your lives, without any plan on your part, you'll come to see suffering that will break your heart. When it happens, and it will, don't turn away from it; turn toward it. That is the moment when change is born.”&lt;cite&gt; - Melinda&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;I strongly encourage you to listen to or read the address. They speak of some very serious real-world issues. They also give us an insight into what has made them so successful. They have drive, ambition, optimism, and focus in trying to solve several big problems. In summation - they are very passionate about what they do. The passion they have drives them to find solutions to those problems. So how do you discover what you are really passionate about? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Concept vs reality: where push comes to shove.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;Several years ago we ran across the word: Wantrepreneur. The definition of this is someone who really wants to start their own business, but has not done so yet. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AlexPirouz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alex Pirouz&lt;/a&gt; in an article in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/242451&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Entrepreneur&lt;/a&gt; had the following 3 things to say about the key characteristics of an entrepreneur vs. wantrepreneur: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/pen-idea-bulb-paper-full.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pen-idea-bulb-paper-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Discover your passion&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageCaption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stock.tookapic.com/photos/7003&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Photo: Krzysztof Puszczyński&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-img&quot;&gt;1. Passionate about business&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h4&quot;&gt;If you are not 100 percent convinced and passionate about your product or service, why should anyone else be?... In my opinion all real entrepreneurs are driven by their passion and love for business, wantrepreneurs are driven by the idea of being an entrepreneur&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;quote-before-h4&quot;&gt;2. Takes massive action&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h4&quot;&gt;Real entrepreneurs do what they say they’re going to do;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;quote-before-h4&quot;&gt;3. Sacrifice&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h4&quot;&gt;It’s ridiculous the roller coaster of emotions you have to go through in order to start, grow and eventually exit your own business.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;I know many people who would love to “be their own boss” or “do something meaningful in business” or “not work for the man” - but are hoping to stumble into something that works for them in business. Being an entrepreneur requires a boatload of passion for what you are doing.
This still leaves us some big questions - how do I find what I am passionate about to drive me towards success? I don’t really want to start my own business, but I want to be part of something awesome -  Is passion only for entrepreneurs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Is passion only for entrepreneurs?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;Obviously not. Sometimes you may find passion being part of something that already exists. Being passionate doesn’t mean that you have to create at your own original content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/summer-photographer-pier-adventure.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/summer-photographer-pier-adventure.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Surfing was my passion&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageCaption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://snapwiresnaps.tumblr.com/post/102448765899/mark-skovorodko-markskovorodkocom-free&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Photo: Mark Skovorodko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;I am extremely passionate about bodyboarding, although you may not guess that since I live in Dallas, Texas. This passion drove me to push past my limits to achieve some amazingly beautiful, yet simple moments between me and nature. The drive was to feel connected to something bigger than I was, to experience a peace with the ocean, yet balanced with excitement. I surfed waves bigger than I was comfortable with, learned maneuvers which took years to perfect, and woke up well before dawn as a teenager to experience what we refer to as a “dawn patrol” - I hungered for more on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;Passion for your daily employment needs to be the same way. If you are not passionate about what you are doing with your life, then perhaps taking a personal inventory of where you are headed is necessary. Working with a team or part of a great organization can also bring that same enthusiasm. Your passion may require you to align yourself to an existing opportunity which fulfils your hunger to contribute. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;But Dave, how do you have any passion for accounting/bookkeeping?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;I ask myself this question by way of example. I once gave a lecture to two different groups of Master degree students at University of Texas - Dallas. I posed the question: '&lt;em&gt;Who here loves accounting?&lt;/em&gt;' Out of the approximately 100 students I asked the question of, only a handful responded positively. Unfortunately, I wasn’t and still am not surprised. The reality is many people pursue employment which they consider 'safe' or 'stable'. The truth is - no company, industry, or profession is truly safe from change. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Heraclitus&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Heraclitus of Ephesus&lt;/a&gt; said:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p pullquote&quot;&gt;Everything changes and nothing stands still.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/black-and-white-car-vehicle-vintage-full.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/black-and-white-car-vehicle-vintage-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dirty jobs can be very rewarding&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageCaption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gratisography.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Photo: Ryan McGuire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;There are many jobs that, on the outside, appear boring or dull, or even useless. However, if you have ever watched an episode of “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.discovery.com/tv-shows/dirty-jobs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dirty Jobs with Mike Rowe&lt;/a&gt;” you will see people who are passionate about some of the most &lt;strong&gt;literally&lt;/strong&gt; dirty jobs in the world. The common thread with these people is they all understand that they are truly making a difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;At Zenkeep - I have a passion for working with entrepreneurs and helping businesses grow and become more efficient. I grew up in an Entrepreneur's home. Our family experienced the impact of a changing economy in South Africa during the 1990's, and the closing of a family business. The reality is a high number of business fail within the first 5 years of business. Our family business survived an incredible 17 years. Statistically, by year 17 only 25% of businesses remain. This is the chart from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bls.gov/bdm/entrepreneurship/entrepreneurship.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/bdm_chart3.png&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/bdm_chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;most businesses don't last forever&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;
Zenkeep aims to provide a missing piece for many small businesses - technical expertise in systems as it relates to accounting and bookkeeping. We also provide much of the work when it comes to bookkeeping and financial analysis. I feel a sense of satisfaction about making that contribution to our clients. At Zenkeep - I am also very passionate about working with members of my family and having great partnerships in my work-environment. I wrote a post awhile back about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/synergy-in-partnerships&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;synergy in partnerships&lt;/a&gt;. I care about working with people I trust and who value my contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Find your passion by discovering where you can contribute &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;Passion comes from facing the problems you have experienced in life. It comes from identifying challenges in your life and the lives of people you care about. Any great organization or movement is supported by people who care very deeply about making a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;I wish you luck and optimism in identifying your passions, and in using them to make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
   
   
   <author>
     <name>Jon Willson</name>
     <email>jon@zenkeep.com</email>
   </author>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Client Spotlight: Women’s Medical Associates of North Texas</title>
   <link href="http://www.provencfo.com/blog/business/2015/10/16/Client-Spotlight-Womens"/>
   <updated>2015-10-16T01:19:19-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.provencfo.com/blog/business/2015/10/16/Client-Spotlight-Womens</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-h2&quot;&gt;Tell us about your business?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mckinneywomens.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Womens Medical Associates of North Texas&lt;/a&gt; is one of the first-established Ob/Gyn practices in Collin County. Dr. Rajala started the practice some 25 years ago. While many of his patients are residents of the county, those who have moved outside of Collin continue to visit to keep Dr. Rajala as their OB/GYN and Primary Care Physician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;
We’re now seeing generations of obstetric patients— the babies I delivered early in my practice are now having children of their own, and it’s flattering that many of them choose me as their Ob/Gyn. Recently, I had the joy of delivering the child of two people that I had delivered many years ago. Does that make me a ‘grand-doctor’?&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;One of the things Dr. Rajala loves doing most is caring for pregnant patients and bringing babies into the world. He estimates he has delivered well over 20,000 babies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote lass=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;I can’t imagine not being able to deliver babies. I am blessed to have the most rewarding job anyone could hope for. We develop relationships with our patients that last a lifetime. We get to be with many of our patients when their children are born, hear stories about their kids’ accomplishments, and help them stay healthy over the years.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;
Services include annual health and wellness exams, menopause management, Obstetrics (Pregnancy), High Risk Pregnancies, family planning, fertility treatment, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;Times change, children grow, but some things never change.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mckinneywomens.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Client-Stories-Womens-Medical-Associates-of-North-Texas-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Women&amp;#039;s Medical Associates Advertisement image&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;What is the vision for the company?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h3&quot;&gt;We really want to continue to provide quality care and to become more and more efficient with the ever-changing healthcare system without compromising the quality of the care provided. At the end of the day we just want to make a difference.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;How has using Zenkeep changed the business?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h3&quot;&gt;Since engaging Zenkeep we've been able to remove the majority of pain points from the business side of things. Rather than working harder, we're able to work smarter.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;The team over at Women's Medical Associates take advantage of the monthly Key Performance Indicator reports provided by Zenkeep to help them manage their financial targets and metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;These reports help us know exactly where we are at as a business, financially. We compare each month to prior periods and determine whether we're hitting targets we set for the year.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;quote-before-h4&quot;&gt;We have better reporting and goal setting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-h4&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Client-Stories-Womens-Medical-Associates-of-North-Texas-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Doctor charts and graphs&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;Zenkeep helped us identify some leases which weren't beneficial to us. Zenkeep helped us re-negotiate these and secured us better financing. These kinds of things really help us as we try to provide affordable health care services.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;quote-before-h4&quot;&gt;We were able to restructure our balance sheet to keep our costs down&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h4&quot;&gt;As healthcare has changed in the US, more and more attention is required on the business side of providing care, than actually providing the care itself... which is why we all got into this field to begin with. Now with the addition of Zenkeep, we're able to spend more time focusing on providing quality care, and less time worrying about the bookkeeping, managerial accounting, and financial planning side of the business.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;quote-after-h4&quot;&gt;We are able to do more of what we love&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Interested in taking your Medical Practice to the next level?&lt;br /&gt;Learn more about Zenkeep’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/services.html&quot;&gt;programs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
   
   
   <author>
     <name>Dave Willson</name>
     <email>dave@zenkeep.com</email>
   </author>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Small Business Accounting: Understanding the Balance Sheet</title>
   <link href="http://www.provencfo.com/blog/accounting/2015/10/07/BalanceSheet"/>
   <updated>2015-10-07T01:19:19-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.provencfo.com/blog/accounting/2015/10/07/BalanceSheet</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion and experience, &lt;strong&gt;the Balance Sheet is the most neglected and least understood financial document in the small business world&lt;/strong&gt;. Too often a small business owner will skip the Balance Sheet entirely to focus solely on the Income Statement. Even if the Balance Sheet is utilized in decision making - it is often only the Cash &amp;amp; Cash Equivalents line item. Two significant issues exist from ignoring the balance sheet. First, the biggest misclassification of entries occurs on the Balance Sheet. Second, a great wealth of knowledge is missed from not correctly interpreting the picture created from Balance Sheet data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;I was reminded the other day about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.magiceye.com/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Magic Eye website&quot;&gt;3D Magic Eye&lt;/a&gt; pictures. This was the 90's phenomenon that drove everyone crazy. I remember checking out these horrible books from the library that contained hundreds of blurry, repeating images. Unfortunately, I wasn't able to decipher anything. Any guesses what the picture below is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;despised&lt;/strong&gt; these things as a kid. I spent countless hours at the library going crossed eyed hoping to see the hidden treasures within. One day a friend, far more experienced than I at 'seeing' the magic pictures, described the process necessary to accurately see and interpret the image. Only then was I able to look at these images and understand the picture within. I liken the process of understanding the Balance Sheet to a Magic Eye image. It takes practice, patience, and concerted effort to understand the picture created by the financial information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This week we review a basic example of a Balance Sheet. I have included some of the issues we see when looking at company financial statements. Here are four lessons for reviewing your Balance Sheet:&amp;lt;/hp&amp;gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-p&quot;&gt;Lesson 1: Remember the Accounting Equation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-h3&quot;&gt;Assets = Liabilities + Equity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-05-at-8.53.48-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-05-at-8.53.48-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Demo Balance Sheet&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt; It really is that simple. When presented in a Balance Sheet the Assets Section is listed at the top and the Liabilities and Equity Section is listed below. Whatever the company &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:1.2em;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;OWNS&lt;/span&gt; is listed as an Asset and whatever the company &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:1.2em;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;OWES&lt;/span&gt; is listed as a Liability. Equity is simply the difference between those numbers. Equity can be separated into many different categories - but remember that at the end of the day it represents the difference between what is owned and owed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;
Assets = What the company owns.&lt;br /&gt;
Liabilities = What the company owes.&lt;br /&gt;
Equity = The difference between what is owned and owed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Lesson 2: Everything is ordered&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;Take a look at the assets of this Demo Company:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/assets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Assets from Demo Company&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive center-block&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;Everything is listed in relationship to liquidity. In other words, the balance sheet is organized by how quickly things can be converted into cash. The sooner it can be converted into cash, the higher it is on the list. A checking account is entirely cash. It is the best example of cash - except for the actual currency in my wallet (But who carries cash anymore? I certainly don't). In our example, the accounts receivable (or the money owed to the business in the normal course of events through sales invoices) is listed next. We don't have any buildings or non-current, intangible assets listed on the statement - but the harder it is to squeeze cash out of an asset quickly - the lower its placement on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/4a296100b5ca8e1de017a64aa2db7e39.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/4a296100b5ca8e1de017a64aa2db7e39.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cash&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-407&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;The same is true for liabilities. The sooner an item needs to be paid, the higher its placement on the list. If it requires payment tomorrow (converted from cash) then it is at the top of the list. When an item does not need to be paid to the lender for 10 years, it is listed lower down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote quote-after-p&quot;&gt;Revenue is vanity...margin is sanity...cash is king.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;quote-before-h4&quot;&gt;
Cash is King.
Everything is ordered by its relationship to cash.
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Lesson 3: Identify issues before comparison&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;You may have already noticed a few issues with the reliability of this Balance Sheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Cash is displaying a credit (negative asset) balance of $4,946&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Computer Equipment is displaying a credit (negative asset) balance of $829.87&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;An Historical Adjustment account exists with a credit (positive liability) balance $4,130.98&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;First, let's discuss the problem with cash&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h4&quot;&gt;So, cash being a negative number is 'sorta a big deal'. This number isn't supposed to be negative, since it is technically impossible to have negative cash in your wallet. However, accounting is like the mirror of Galadriel in the Lord of the Rings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;For [accounting] … shows many things… things that were… things that are… and some things… that have not yet come to pass.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lordoftherings.net/home.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; - J.R.R. Tolkein, &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;Cash is negative, in our example, because the company has already committed those funds for use. The company has properly recorded all the checks they have sent out, and all the expenses occurring on the debit card. The problem is that the business doesn't have sufficient funds to cover those checks when they clear the bank. The business needs to deposit additional cash into tthe account, or some of those checks are going to bounce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;However, cash is not supposed to be negative on a regular basis. This is not a healthy sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;Secondly, lets look at our negative computer equipment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h4&quot;&gt;Again, we have an asset that is a credit (negative) balance. I opened up the detail of this item on the Balance Sheet and found the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-06-at-9.29.48-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Computer Equipment detail&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-441&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;
It appears that an attempt was made to reclassify equipment that had been coded erroneously to Office Equipment. However, the journal entry to fix the coding has been made in the wrong direction. The Office Equipment account should have been credited instead of debited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-06-at-9.32.44-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Equipment reclass journal&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-444&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;This requires a simple fix to reverse and correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;Lastly, what is this historical adjustment account?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h4&quot;&gt;Often, when we inherit a set of books, there are a few accounts with current balances which are not an accurate reflection of reality. In our Demo Company example, the Xero software provides an aggregator account to lump all the &lt;em&gt;&quot;unknowns&quot;&lt;/em&gt; together. When this company converted to Xero the system forced the following entry: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-06-at-9.40.16-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Conversion Entry for Demo Company&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;In other words, when the person converting this file was working through the numbers, &quot;something&quot; didn't add up. That &quot;something&quot; was $4,130.98 of &quot;I don't know what&quot;. The accountant at year end needs to do 1 of 2 things. Either they need to work backwards through all the historical transactions to find that &quot;I don't know what&quot;, or they need to deal with it in the current period. If the amount is large enough - the search is necessary, otherwise we can simply journal entry the $4,130.98 into the current year Income Statement as an &quot;extraordinary adjustment&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;These issues happen in the real world, so understanding what the transactions in your &quot;anomaly&quot; accounts are imperative.&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;
Identify and understand abnormal balances in accounts.&lt;br /&gt;
Identify and understand unusual accounts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Lesson 4: Comparisons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;I wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/small-business-accounting-understanding-the-income-statement/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Income Statement article&quot;&gt;article last week about the Income Statement&lt;/a&gt; which contained a lesson about comparisons. The process of comparing the Balance Sheet to previous months, quarters, and years is just as important. Without a comparison, it is impossible to gauge which direction a company is headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Cat: Where are you going?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Alice: Which way should I go?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Cat: That depends on where you are going.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Alice: I don’t know.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Cat: Then it doesn’t matter which way you go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/329837-cat-where-are-you-going-alice-which-way-should-i&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; - Lewis Carroll, &lt;em&gt;Alice in Wonderland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;Here are a few examples of comparison questions I would ask against the previous month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Has my Cash &amp;amp; Cash Equivalents Balance increased or decreased over last month?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;max-width:900px; margin:30px auto;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-07-at-9.52.28-AM.png&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-07-at-9.52.28-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cash Balance Comparison&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Have I increased my receivables? Am I collecting my outstanding receivables quick enough? (This is a lesson for another day)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;max-width:900px; margin:30px auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-07-at-9.52.34-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Accounts Receivable Comparison&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Have I purchased more Fixed Assets? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;max-width:900px; margin:30px auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-07-at-9.52.39-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;PPE Comparison&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Am I generating more expenses that I haven't paid for yet through the Accounts Payable? Why is that balance increasing? Am I paying my bills too early or too late?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;max-width:900px; margin:30px auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-07-at-9.52.44-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Accounts Payable Comparison&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is my current year earnings increasing or decreasing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;max-width:900px; margin:30px auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Screen-Shot-2015-10-07-at-9.52.49-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;CY Earnings comparison&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;Comparison against previous results displays the direction of the business.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;The Big Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;Just as the Cat explained to Alice, the same holds true for business. Knowing what to do next depends on where you have come from and your desired destination. The Balance sheet helps us understand where you have come from and the current direction of the business financially. When utilized effectively along with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/3-great-accounting-tools-every-business-needs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Budgets, forecasts, and goals&quot;&gt;budgets, forecasts, and goals,&lt;/a&gt; the balance sheet can drive both long and short-term decision making. We help businesses restructure their balance sheet on paper as well as their debt, to ensure they are reducing overheads and maximizing their cash usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;What are some of the areas of the Balance Sheet that you love reviewing on a weekly, monthly, or annual basis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
   
   
   <author>
     <name>Dave Willson</name>
     <email>dave@zenkeep.com</email>
   </author>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Small Business Accounting: Understanding the Income Statement</title>
   <link href="http://www.provencfo.com/blog/accounting/2015/09/28/IncomeStatement"/>
   <updated>2015-09-28T01:19:19-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.provencfo.com/blog/accounting/2015/09/28/IncomeStatement</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking a lot lately about what Zenkeep actually delivers as a final product/service to our customers. Ultimately, with our bookkeeping service, we have the goal to produce relevant and reliable financial statements to our clients in a timely manner. The use of &lt;a title=&quot;Xero&quot; href=&quot;http://xero.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Xero&lt;/a&gt; cloud software, and the tools from add-on partners such as &lt;a title=&quot;Vend&quot; href=&quot;http://vendhq.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vend&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a title=&quot;Gusto&quot; href=&quot;http://gusto.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gusto&lt;/a&gt;, make it possible for that timely manner to be as near to real-time as humanly possible. However, the utility of Financial Statements isn't just that they should arrive in a timely way, but rather they should enable you to understand your current business and evaluate your future strategies and goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;I wrote a blog post last week about &lt;a title=&quot;Forecasting, budgets, and financial goals&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.zenkeep.com/accounting/2015/09/22/3%20great%20accounting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;forecasting, budgets, and financial goals&lt;/a&gt; which explains a few effective ways for a small business owner to utilize their financial statements. Through a series of blog posts I want to break down the financial statements in a way that is useful to a small business owner (&lt;strong&gt;rather than to a Wall-street investor&lt;/strong&gt;). I will provide bookkeeping tips and accounting practices that we use with our own business and for many of our clients. Most of our clients have wanted or needed help understanding their small business accounting needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;Today, we'll start with the Income Statement (Profit and Loss Statement) using a simple example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-10.20.46-AM.png&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-275&quot; src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-09-28-at-10.20.46-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Income Statement - Small Business Financial Accounting&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-p&quot;&gt;Lesson 1: Cash vs Accrual - when are items recorded?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;
First, I want to define the difference between &quot;&lt;em&gt;Cash Basis&lt;/em&gt;&quot; and &quot;&lt;em&gt;Accrual Basis&lt;/em&gt;&quot;. In accounting - we have to define everything. &quot;&lt;em&gt;Cash Basis&lt;/em&gt;&quot; is simply recording transactions when they impact the bank account. &quot;&lt;em&gt;Accrual Basis&lt;/em&gt;&quot; means that we are trying to record the transactions when they occur in reality. For example - imagine you agree to do some work for a customer. The customer agrees to pay you $1,000 when the work is completed. Using &quot;&lt;em&gt;Cash Basis&lt;/em&gt;&quot; - we record the transaction as a sale when the $1,000 shows up in your bank account. On the other hand, using &quot;&lt;em&gt;Accrual Basis&lt;/em&gt;&quot; we record the transaction when the agreement was made. The disparity between the two systems becomes a bigger deal the longer it takes for the cash to show up. If the cash does not show up until the following month - then the sale gets recorded next month using &quot;&lt;em&gt;Cash Basis&lt;/em&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;When reading your financial statements - it is important to understand when the transactions are being recorded.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h4&quot;&gt;To learn more about &quot;&lt;em&gt;Cash&lt;/em&gt;&quot; vs. &quot;&lt;em&gt;Accrual Basis&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, check out the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;li-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Accounting Coach - Accrual Basis&quot; href=&quot;http://www.accountingcoach.com/blog/acrrual-basis-accounting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Accounting Coach - Accrual Basis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Legal Encyclopedia - Cash vs. Accrual&quot; href=&quot;http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/cash-vs-accrual-accounting-29513.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Legal Encyclopedia - Cash vs. Accrual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Lesson 2: The power of comparison and assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;Next, I want to call your attention to the dates and the idea of comparison. Financial Statements are useful on their own, however, they are far more useful to you if they are compared to other financial statements. In the example above, we are looking at a comparison against 3 previous months of the same business. We also have the usefulness of looking at the Year to Date numbers through August 31st. The ability to compare financial statements allows us to make some very powerful assumptions when reading financial statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;Here are a few examples of assumptions we can make based on comparison against previous months:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Take a look at the top line revenue account, &quot;&lt;em&gt;400 - Sales&lt;/em&gt;&quot;. I am able to see that the business most likely only started producing revenue in early 2015. There is only $3k in Sales that happened before May of this year. I can see that August was a great month for the business in bringing new business in the door.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-10-02-at-9.44.07-AM.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Sales line item&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All the advertising expense for the year occurred in August. Based on the gross revenue they heavily invested in this area last month. They must have a good reason for doing so.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-10-02-at-9.46.42-AM.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Advertising Line Item&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;They have only started paying Salaries and Wages this month.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-350&quot; src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-10-02-at-10.01.29-AM.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Salaries Line Item&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It appears that the rent entry and the utility entry in August is missing. This is because they only delivered the rent check to the landlord after the end of the month. &lt;strong&gt;(The example we are looking at is a cash basis financial statement - so the expense is recorded when the money leaves the account)&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-353&quot; src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-10-02-at-10.04.24-AM.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Rent Line Item&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-351&quot; src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-10-02-at-10.02.50-AM.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Utilities Line Item&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;While the bottom line Net Income Account is positive in June and May - this doesn't mean the company was doing financially better in those months.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-354&quot; src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-10-02-at-10.05.28-AM.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Net Income Line Item&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-before-li&quot;&gt;
Wall street uses comparison of financial statements to make evaluations on whether a stock is a buy, sell, or hold. A financial analyst will not only compare a company to previous versions of itself, but also to other companies. While you may not be able to compare yourself to readily available financial statements of your competitors, you are able to make some assumptions and do some detective work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;Here are a few examples of questions we can ask based on a comparison against competitors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Are my competitors paying 15% for their cost of goods sold?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Based on the number of employees that I have vs. my competitors - do I have more or less?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Am I paying industry average for rents? Have I leased a space that is too big?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Am I spending more or less than my competitors on advertising? Do I need to change my advertising strategy to be noticed by my customers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;Assumptions and comparisons help you help you understand trends and make adjustments to overall strategy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Lesson 3: Work from biggest to smallest&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;Rather than focusing on each individual line item initially, I always start with the &quot;Big Ticket&quot; items. When reviewing financial statements of Wall Street companies, the financials are dramatically simplified to help investors understand the basics. The details are available as supplements and notes (hundreds of pages of supplements and notes) - but the data that is most important are the simple pieces. Start with what is the most important pieces and work towards least important. Did the company make a profit or loss this month? What was my gross revenue? Does my Cost of Goods as a percentage look right? Did I spend too much on Rent or Wages, or office expense? Why did I spend $1,235.67 on Dues and Subscriptions in July... what was I thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Screen-Shot-2015-10-02-at-10.18.12-AM.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Subscriptions Line Item&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-img&quot;&gt;Remember to not sweat the small stuff as you start getting into the details&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Lesson 4: Don't ignore the details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;Although I suggest you work from biggest to smallest, don't forget - more often than not - the problems lie in the areas which receive no attention. In the example statement, we would simply click on each of the numbers that we want detail on. I would examine &quot;&lt;em&gt;Office Expenses&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, &quot;&lt;em&gt;Consulting &amp;amp; Accounting&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, &quot;&lt;em&gt;Printing &amp;amp; Stationery&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, and &quot;&lt;em&gt;Repairs and Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;&quot; just to review the details. I would perform a quick spot check to make sure the transactions occurring in these accounts looked right. The example actually has meals and entertainment coded into the &quot;&lt;em&gt;Printing &amp;amp; Stationery&lt;/em&gt;&quot; account - which is a big no-no when it comes time for taxes. Without looking for details - this company might have a small tax issue on its hands if coding meals into an office expense related category is regular practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;Look for the hidden costs. Don't be afraid to look at the transactions behind each total on the statements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;Lesson 5: Understand the lesson the picture is painting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;The Income Statement produces a picture (in our example it is a very simple picture). What does the picture teach us? This particular example teaches me that the business is new, that it is barely getting off the ground when it comes to sales. It shows me the business needs more capital to cope with the coming months - since the growth of income doesn't out-weigh the expense growth. The trend shows me that if the business has no capital sources to fund the growth - then expenses need to be curbed (most likely from advertising). It shows me that the company has terrific Gross Margins (15c to produce $1 of income) and that if the business is able to sell more and curb the operational expenses as a fixed expense, then the business is capable of remaining a strong going-concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;The Big Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-h3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/screen_shot_laptop.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screen_shot_laptop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Chart on computer&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-369&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;So to review, ask yourself the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What am I looking at?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What is the time frame of data and do I have any comparisons to work with?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do I first focus on the big important stuff?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do I know where I could have costs hiding from me?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Did I find a lesson? What am I being taught? Do I understand the big picture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-li&quot;&gt;Here is a picture of a &lt;a title=&quot;Big NASA Picture&quot; href=&quot;http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/thumbnails/image/hs-2015-02-a-hires_jpg.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;big picture&lt;/a&gt; to remind you of these steps. Following these steps will set the groundwork for understanding your business as you grow. At Zenkeep, we focus on simplifying the Income Statement as much as possible to ensure the lessons are easy to understand and apply. A complicated financial statement is just a simple financial statement with more detail on the front page.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
   
   
   <author>
     <name>Dave Willson</name>
     <email>dave@zenkeep.com</email>
   </author>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>3 great accounting tools every business needs</title>
   <link href="http://www.provencfo.com/blog/accounting/2015/09/22/3greataccounting"/>
   <updated>2015-09-22T01:19:19-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.provencfo.com/blog/accounting/2015/09/22/3greataccounting</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Forecasting, budgets, and financial goals - Why bother? Similar to climbing a mountain, a business owner needs to understand the route, the risk, and the reward. A good plan is necessary to tackle the highest peaks and reach the summit of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;It is a capital mistake to theorize before one has data. Insensibly one begins to twist facts to suit theories, instead of theories to suit facts.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/work/quotes/8462586-sherlock-holmes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; - Arthur Conan Doyle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;Data drives decisions. I might end up writing this a thousand times... but you first need to have some useful data before arriving at a conclusion. I want you to understand the difference between a forecast, a budget, and a financial goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;First, you need to create a forecast. A &lt;strong&gt;forecast&lt;/strong&gt; is an exercise in identifying where the business is going based on current and historical trends. For example, a non-cyclical business averaging $10,000 a month for the first 6 months of a year is forecasted to do $120,000 in gross revenues. Sit down and review your financial statements. If you need to... create a straight-line graph of the big category numbers, e.g. Gross Revenue, Cost of Goods/Services, and Operating Expenses. Simply take a ruler and try average those trend lines out a whole year from today. See where you end up. Do you have sufficient revenue to cover the expenses? Are you trending upwards across all fronts or are your expenditures growing quicker than revenues?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;Next, you need to formulate a budget. A &lt;strong&gt;budget&lt;/strong&gt; creates limits around potential and expected expenditures within a certain time period. Ultimately, a budget is used to control spending habits and ensure that the different areas of a business receive appropriate funding. Using your historical data and your forecast, can you limit your expenses in certain areas and still achieve the same gross revenues? Can you improve the bottom line at a greater rate by reducing certain expenses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;Lastly, and most importantly, you need to create a goal. A &lt;strong&gt;financial goal&lt;/strong&gt; is how we move forward. This is not just an exercise in accounting. It is the creation of a plan to guide the strategy of business. Goals need to be defined and measurable. Most importantly goals need to be attainable. Financial goals are not based on historical or current trends, they are indicators of the changes in strategy or direction of a company. Your goals are used to motivate and define the size of the mountain you are climbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/people-coffee-notes-tea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;people sitting and taking notes&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;auto&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;So grab &lt;del datetime=&quot;2015-09-22T14:21:00+00:00&quot;&gt;a piece of paper and a pen&lt;/del&gt; your laptop, sit down by yourself, or with your financial team, and work the numbers to understand where you are at and where you are headed. Create a written financial goal. Remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p pullquote&quot;&gt;If you fail to plan, you are planning to fail.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/460142-if-you-fail-to-plan-you-are-planning-to-fail&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; - Benjamin Franklin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
   
   
   <author>
     <name>Dave Willson</name>
     <email>dave@zenkeep.com</email>
   </author>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Understanding the accounting equation</title>
   <link href="http://www.provencfo.com/blog/accounting/2015/09/21/Understandingtheaccounting"/>
   <updated>2015-09-21T01:19:19-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.provencfo.com/blog/accounting/2015/09/21/Understandingtheaccounting</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;A picture is worth a thousand words &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;I have spent a long time studying accounting and am still learning. I love that accounting is both a science and an art form. In my final year in my bachelors degree in Accounting I came home one day and announced to my wife that I finally understood the accounting equation. Granted this was after studying accountancy in high school, earning an associates in business and certificate in accounting and having worked in an accounting office for several years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;The accounting equation, in theory, is rather simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-p&quot;&gt;Assets = Liabilities + Equity &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Assets&lt;/strong&gt; are everything you own or are owed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Liabilities&lt;/strong&gt; are everything you owe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Equity&lt;/strong&gt; is made up of all the contributions and withdrawals of the shareholders as well as the current and retained earnings of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;The books always have to balance. We use debits and credits as a double entry system to keep the accounting equation in balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-p&quot;&gt;Debits = Credits &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;When you want an asset account to go up - you record a debit. When you want a liability or equity account to go up - you record a credit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;At the end of the day, the objective is to create a relevant and reliable picture which contains immense value to the stakeholders involved in the business. If your only objective is to create reports useful to the tax man - as a business owner you are missing out in understanding a huge side to your business. The picture we create is capable of telling a very detailed story about how a business is being operated. The details allow us to see operational deficiencies, strategy shortcomings, or massive opportunities and strengths to capitalize on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
   
   
   <author>
     <name>Dave Willson</name>
     <email>dave@zenkeep.com</email>
   </author>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>This is an example title</title>
   <link href="http://www.provencfo.com/blog/example/2015/09/01/ExamplePost"/>
   <updated>2015-09-01T01:19:19-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.provencfo.com/blog/example/2015/09/01/ExamplePost</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is a standalone h2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This is a standalone h2&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This is a standalone h3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h3&gt;This is a standalone h3&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;This is a standalone h4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is a standalone h4&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a standalone p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a standalone p&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a standalone li inside of a ul&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a standalone li inside of a ul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;This is a standalone li inside of a ul&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;This is a standalone li inside of a ul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a standalone li inside of an ol&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a standalone li inside of an ol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;This is a standalone li inside of an ol&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;This is a standalone li inside of an ol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;This is a standalone blockquote&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;This is a standalone blockquote&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;This is a standalone pullquote&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;This is a standalone pullquote&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is an h2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-h2&quot;&gt;This is an h3 after an h2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This is an h2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-h2&quot;&gt;This is an h3 after an h2&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This is an h3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-h3&quot;&gt;This is an h4 after an h3.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h3&gt;This is an h3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-h3&quot;&gt;This is an h4 after an h3.&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is an h2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-h2&quot;&gt;This is an h4 after an h2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This is an h2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-h2&quot;&gt;This is an h4 after an h2&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;This is an h4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-h4&quot;&gt;This is an h2 after an h4.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is an h4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-h4&quot;&gt;This is an h2 after an h4.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;This is an h4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-h4&quot;&gt;This is an h3 after an h4.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is an h4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-h4&quot;&gt;This is an h3 after an h4.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This is an h3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-h3&quot;&gt;This is an h2 after an h3.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h3&gt;This is an h3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-h3&quot;&gt;This is an h2 after an h3.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This is an h2 after a divider then by a p&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h2&quot;&gt;This is an paragraph after an h2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This is an h2 after a divider then by a p&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h2&quot;&gt;This is an paragraph after an h2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This is an h3 after a divider then by a p&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;This is an paragraph after an h3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This is an h3 after a divider then by a p&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h3&quot;&gt;This is an paragraph after an h3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This is an h4 after a divider then by a p&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h4&quot;&gt;This is an paragraph after an h4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This is an h4 after a divider then by a p&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-h4&quot;&gt;This is an paragraph after an h4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This is an paragraph after a divider then by an h2 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-p&quot;&gt;This is an h2 following a p&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-divider&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-section-divider&quot;&gt;This is an paragraph after a divider then by an h2 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-p&quot;&gt;This is an h2 following a p&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an paragraph followed by an h3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-p&quot;&gt;This is an h3 following a p&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an paragraph followed by an h3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-p&quot;&gt;This is an h3 following a p&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an paragraph followed by an h4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;This is an h4 following a p&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an paragraph followed by an h4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-p&quot;&gt;This is an h4 following a p&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropCap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropCapContent&quot;&gt;his is an paragraph that starts with a dropcap. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Etiam consectetur ut ipsum non egestas. Quisque cursus odio ut facilisis porttitor. Donec malesuada nec neque pellentesque sodales.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
	&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropCap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropCapContent&quot;&gt;his is an paragraph that starts with a dropcap.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a p followed by a blockquote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;&quot;This is a blockquote, following a p, which is followed by a p&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;This is a p after a blockquote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a p followed by a blockquote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-p&quot;&gt;&quot;This is a blockquote, following a p, which is followed by a p&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote-before-p&quot;&gt;This is a p after a blockquote&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is an h2 followed by a blockquote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h2&quot;&gt;This is a blockquote, following a h2, which is followed by a h2&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;quote-before-h2&quot;&gt;This is an h2 after a blockquote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This is an h2 followed by a blockquote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h2&quot;&gt;This is a blockquote, following a h2, which is followed by a h2&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;quote-before-h2&quot;&gt;This is an h2 after a blockquote&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This is an h3 followed by a blockquote&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h3&quot;&gt;This is a blockquote, following a h3, which is followed by a h3&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;quote-before-h3&quot;&gt;This is an h3 after a blockquote&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h3&gt;This is an h3 followed by a blockquote&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h3&quot;&gt;This is a blockquote, following a h3, which is followed by a h3&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;quote-before-h3&quot;&gt;This is an h3 after a blockquote&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;This is an h4 followed by a blockquote&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h4&quot;&gt;This is a blockquote, following a h4, which is followed by a h4&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;quote-before-h4&quot;&gt;This is an h4 after a blockquote&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is an h4 followed by a blockquote&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote-after-h4&quot;&gt;This is a blockquote, following a h4, which is followed by a h4&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;quote-before-h4&quot;&gt;This is an h4 after a blockquote&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is an h2 followed by an image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-h2&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageCaption&quot;&gt;This is an image caption&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This is an h2 followed by an image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-h2&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imageCaption&quot;&gt;This is an image caption&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This is an h3 followed by an image&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-h3&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h3&gt;This is an h3 followed by an image&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-h3&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;This is an h4 followed by an image&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-h4&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is an h4 followed by an image&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-h4&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a p followed by an image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a p followed by an image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a p followed by another p &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;This is a p after another p &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a p followed by another p &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-p&quot;&gt;This is a p after another p &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a p followed by a li (either ul or ol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;li-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after a p&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after a p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a p followed by a li (either ul or ol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;li-after-p&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after a p&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after a p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li before a p&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li before a p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-li&quot;&gt;This is a p following a li (either ul or ol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li before a p&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li before a p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-li&quot;&gt;This is a p following a li (either ul or ol)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li before an li&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li before an li&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-li&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after an li&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after an li&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li before an li&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li before an li&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-li&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after an li&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after an li&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-373&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;This is an image followed by a p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-after-img&quot;&gt;This is an image followed by a p&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-373&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-img&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after an img&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after an img&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-373&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;li-after-img&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after an img&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a li after an img&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-373&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-img&quot;&gt;This is an image followed by a h2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;h2-after-img&quot;&gt;This is an image followed by a h2&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-img&quot;&gt;This is an image followed by a h3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h3-after-img&quot;&gt;This is an image followed by a h3&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.zenkeep.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/stereogram_magic_eye_1900x1378_2560x1600_wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d magic eye wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-img&quot;&gt;This is an image followed by a h4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;examplelineonly&quot;&gt;
&lt;xmp&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; class=&quot;popup-link&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;wallpaperno.com_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wallpaper&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;h4-after-img&quot;&gt;This is an image followed by a h4&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidawillson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dave Willson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
   
   
   <author>
     <name>Dave Willson</name>
     <email>dave@zenkeep.com</email>
   </author>
   
 </entry>
 

</feed>
